<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-02T19:04:52+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MAKE A WEB</title><subtitle>We build websites to help businesses thrive with a visual brand.
</subtitle><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><entry><title type="html">What is SEO?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/what-is-seo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is SEO?" /><published>2019-02-01T03:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T03:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/what-is-seo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/what-is-seo">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary&lt;/b&gt;: SEO stands for &quot;search engine optimisation.&quot; Improving on your website ranking is an essential part of running an online business. This article from Google explains &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/70897&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;how search works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Do you need SEO?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    My job and my overall life goal is to help you, the people. Instead of seeing this as a sales pitch why not view it as a helpful guide to ensure the success of &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; future success. So without further ado, yes you do need search engine optimisation on your website. Having the basic optimisations implemented when your website is created will save you money down the line. This article from Google goes through the topic &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35291?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;do you need seo&lt;/a&gt; very well. It outlines what you can do yourself and will upskill your current knowleadge of the subject. No doubt that if you have a business you must get plenty of emails regarding how different digital companies can improve your search engine ranking. Be careful with who you hire. If implemented incorrectly you can also risk damage to your site and reputation. You can be confident in asking MAKE A WEB to help you with your overall marketing strategy. The video below can be used as a checklist to ensure whoever is doing the work does it right.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row mt-8&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-8 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
          &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/piSvFxV_M04&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let's visualise an example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We have a client that has a car servicing business in Doncaster, Melbourne. The client has told us that they want to get more people from around the local area to find them on the web. Search engine optimisation starts from the very beginning when building a website. Your domain name is your most valuable asset. For example a good domain name for our client would be carservicedoncaster.com.au. Why is this a good domain name? It is a good domain name because it includes all of the words that a customer would type to solve their problem. If the customer typed in &quot;Car Service Doncaster&quot; we have a greater chance to show up in the search results. This is because all of the words are highlighted in the domain name. It all starts upfront with your domain name and then cascades down to the content on your website and many other points. Such as having a website that is accessible, mobile friendly, secure and fast.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How can you save money?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    As a customer you can save money by writing your own content. Having the knowleadge in writing good copy is a different thing and that costs money. Content that is well written and search engine optimised will help your business succeed online. So you should see it more as an investment and not a loss in financial terms. Having a copy writer or upskilling can help drastically with this. Making your website secure via https, accessible, mobile friendly and load quickly are things your most likely going to need a developer for. Using a website generator will handle some of these things for you but not at the level of accuracy a developer would be able to do. Not to mention having a developer to consult can help build idea's and solve problems. Feel free to send me a message anytime about your website and how we can improve it. Remember it all starts from how we get your customers to find you. The video below goes through 7 free tools you can use to rank #1 in Google. MAKE A WEB can provide help with any search engine optimisation tasks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row mt-8&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-12 col-md-8 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
          &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jhnNOlhPbyc&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How can MAKE A WEB help you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    At MAKE A WEB we go through a &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/website-design-process&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website design process&lt;/a&gt; which will ensure your website starts on the best foot forward. People are stringing together websites using generators nowadays to try and save money. However most of these generators don't have the capacity or technology to handle these vital optimisations. We implement these optimisations during the development of any website we create. You may save money using a generator but the success of your website is not guaranteed. That's why using a developer can help. MAKE A WEB can work with you to ensure the success of your business online. Preventing the website from being another outdated website. Imagine a world where your customers view your website as an apple tree. They just keep coming back for more apples. That's what we are trying to achieve here, because, well, who doesn't want to make money selling their own apples.
    This &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/blog/google-search-console-crawl-stats/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article by Neil Patel&lt;/a&gt; explains how to use Google Search Console for maximum SEO power. When building any website MAKE A WEB optimises your website for search which is included in our &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/website-design-process&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website design process&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Search engine optimisation should be considered an objective in your overall marketing strategy. At the end of the day, what good is having a website if your customers can't find it on the web. At MAKE A WEB we like to keep all of this in mind when we are designing our websites. Being able to visualise the end product helps but discussing how you want your customers to find you is an integral part of any website design. This is why we will always ask - what would a customer type into Google to find you?
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Summary: SEO stands for &quot;search engine optimisation.&quot; Improving on your website ranking is an essential part of running an online business. This article from Google explains how search works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Google Analytics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/understanding-google-analytics" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Google Analytics" /><published>2018-02-17T03:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-02-17T03:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/understanding-google-analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/understanding-google-analytics">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Google Analytics is a service that retrieves and displays statistics about website traffic. As some definitions can be confusing, we wrote this document to help you assess and understand your reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google analytics allows you to get a step ahead, well only if you use it right. You can use data to help leverage the business decisions you make on your website. The goal is for it to help with the design of your website and it’s continuous improvement. For example, we can gather the stats for the number of enquiries we have had from a form. Then we can compare that with the amount of specific page views the webpage has received. If we see a huge difference in numbers we can come to a conclusion that maybe a new design would help persuade users to fill out the form. Our goal would be to increase conversion on that form. Using the power of Google Analytics you can easily make data-driven marketing decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is a free service. This means any person with web knowledge, for example, a web developer can implement it on your website. You can then use its website to generate reports. These reports can help analyse what works and what doesn’t work on your website. We can then come to a verdict based on the report on how to improve the users experience on your website. This with the overarching goal of increasing sales. I’ve included a table below with the main definitions you may find in a Google Analytics report for easy digestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered my-4&quot;&gt;
	&lt;colgroup&gt;
		&lt;col /&gt;
		&lt;col /&gt;
	&lt;/colgroup&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td class=&quot;text-center&quot; colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Analytics Terms and Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pageviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;How many visits, total, downloaded and viewed this specific web page.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Defines the information for each page on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique pageviews&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Show how many individual users, total, downloaded and viewed this specific web page – if a computer visits the same page more than once it is no longer considered ‘unique’.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Entrances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;If this is the &lt;/span&gt;first page a visitor enters when viewing the site, it is considered an Entrance.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Avg. Time on Page&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Aggregate mean time spent on each page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Bounce Rate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;The percentage of people that leave after having only &lt;/span&gt;visited one page – a high bounce rate is usually a negative signal, indicating that visitors are unsatisfied and leave, although it could mean they find exactly what they need on the first page.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;% Exit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;If this is the &lt;/span&gt;last page a visitor enters when viewing the site, it is considered an Exit.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Page Value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
			&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;docs-internal-guid-65724336-b6dc-a451-f005-eb6f36ff43a0&quot;&gt;Can be used to assign a monetary value for each visitor on a web page, so you can assess the financial losses within both bounces and exits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://makeaweb.com.au/&quot; title=&quot;MAKE A WEB - Web design - Melbourne&quot;&gt;MAKE A WEB&lt;/a&gt; we like to include Google Analytics in all the websites we create as part of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://makeaweb.com.au/services/digital-marketing&quot; title=&quot;MAKE A WEB - Digital marketing - Melbourne&quot;&gt;Digital marketing&lt;/a&gt;. It allows for you the customer to see the traffic you get to the website. It’s certainly a good feeling to see customers coming to your website. It’s important to know that Google Analytics does, in fact, provide a lot more information than just the amount of visitors. You can also find out the locations of your visitors. You can find out the most popular pages and posts on your website. You can then find out what websites send traffic to your website. If you have an e-commerce website it can help identify the customers shopping behaviour. Once you understand how your users are browsing your website, you can figure out what content they like. Then you can tailor your strategy to help grow your traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final hurrah, Google has so many awesome resources that we can utilise. &lt;a href=&quot;https://analytics.google.com/analytics/academy/course/6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google Analytics for Beginners&lt;/a&gt; offers a full course breakdown and overview on how to become a pro at this stuff, enjoy! I also spent some time reading through an article about certain &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/expert-google-analytics-reports/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Google analytics reports&lt;/a&gt; which was interesting. It shows different types of reports you might find useful on your journey.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Google Analytics is a service that retrieves and displays statistics about website traffic. As some definitions can be confusing, we wrote this document to help you assess and understand your reports.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website design process</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/website-design-process" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website design process" /><published>2018-01-07T03:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-01-07T03:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/website-design-process</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/website-design-process">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Our Website design process is centered around making our customers happy and aware of what is going on during this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first send out a Website design questionnaire. Once completed we analyse and send a Project Proposal with a Quote. If you accept we go ahead and start the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great design is about creating a website that aligns with an overarching strategy. Well-designed websites offer much more than just a visual picture. They attract visitors and help people understand the product, company, and branding through a variety of indicators, encompassing visuals, text, and interactions. That means every element of your site needs to work towards a defined goal. A website isn’t just a business card about what you do. It needs to be part of a strategy to help your business grow. The best way to do this is to publish fresh engaging content to your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals are set out in the Project Proposal. These goals are unique to your business and created based on the answers in the Website design questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;h2&quot;&gt;Milestones&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Goal identification and Scope definition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to work together to help identify the website’s end goal. In close collaboration with you and other stakeholders if possible. For example answering questions like, who is the site for?, What is the website’s primary responsibility?, How should your site be different to your competitors? This is the most important part of any web design process. If these questions aren’t clearly answered in the brief, the whole project can set off in the wrong direction. Scope definition will help us outline a plan so that you can see realistic goals being achieved during the whole Web design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Wireframing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the wireframing process we will create a sitemap. This provides a foundation for any well-designed website. It will give a clear idea of the website’s information architecture. This will help explain the relationship between the various pages and content. Building a site without a sitemap is like building a house without a blueprint. Once that is complete we will collaborate together to create wireframes. Wireframes provide a framework for storing the site’s visual design and content elements. It can help identify potential challenges and gaps in the sitemap. Inevitably ensuring that we create a well designed website with a good information architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Content creation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your websites wireframe is complete you can start with another important aspect of any site: the written content. First, content engages readers and drives them to take the actions necessary to fulfill a site’s goals. This is affected by both the content itself (the writing), and how it’s presented (the typography and structural elements). Dull, lifeless, and overlong content rarely keeps visitors’ attention for long. Short, snappy, and intriguing content grabs them and gets them to click through to other pages. Even if your pages need a lot of content — and often, they do — properly “chunking” that content by breaking it up into short paragraphs supplemented by visuals can help it keep a light, engaging feel. Content also boosts a site’s visibility for search engines. The practice of creation and improving content to rank well in search is known as search engine optimisation, or SEO. Getting your keywords and keyphrases right is essential for the success of any website. My design process focuses on designing websites around SEO. Content that’s well-written, informative, and keyword-rich is more easily picked up by search engines, all of which helps to make the site easier to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Website development and testing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave it to us, we now have to build the website. We will ensure that the website is tested and works in all modern devices and browsers. The website will be tested and validated in relation to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://validator.w3.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Go to World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) website&quot;&gt;World Wide Web Consortium (W3C)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/docs/insights/about&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read about Google Page Speed&quot;&gt;Google Pagespeed Insights&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Find out more about Web Accessibility&quot;&gt;WAVE Web Accessibility Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Launch&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time for everyone’s favorite part of the web design process: When everything has been thoroughly tested, and you’re happy with the site, it’s time to launch. A key thing to remember about the launch stage is that it’s nowhere near the end of the job. The beauty of the web is that it’s never finished. Once the site goes live, you can continually run user testing on new content and features, monitor analytics, and refine your messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Training and consulting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will involve us training you how to update the website using the Content Management System we used to develop your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;h3&quot;&gt;Online support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosting, domain and email support. We can help you with it all. Hosting is what makes your site visible on the web. Your domain name is what makes visitors able to access your hosted website and your email is how they can contact you to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might already have a website with hosting and a domain name. In that case we can just leave it all in place and put our new designed website in its place. However this could cause problems and could already be causing problems such as site speed and performance. In order to obtain a good service we’ll have to transfer the domain name over to a new preferred hosting plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t got a hosting, domain or an email plan setup we can do that for you too. We can buy the domain name you want to be seen at for example www.yourbusiness.com.au and an email like hello@yourbusiness.com.au.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Our Website design process is centered around making our customers happy and aware of what is going on during this process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to edit content in WordPress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/how-to-edit-content-in-wordpress" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to edit content in WordPress" /><published>2017-11-06T04:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-11-06T04:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/how-to-edit-content-in-wordpress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/how-to-edit-content-in-wordpress">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Before you can start anything you need to log in, append &lt;strong&gt;wp-login.php&lt;/strong&gt; to the end of your website address. Then enter your username and password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;www.yourdomain.com.au/&lt;strong&gt;wp-login.php&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once logged in you will be presented with the WordPress dashboard. This is where you’ll navigate to various parts of the CMS (Content Management System). The power is in your hands. For now, just have a look at the left menu where you have various options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have any questions you can always ask your system administrator. Do keep in mind that Google search can also be of huge value here. The WordPress community is huge and any problem experienced has already been solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Adding and editing posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;In the left menu click on posts. You’ll now see a list of posts&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Click on the title of the post you wish to edit&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to add a new post click on posts. Then in the left menu click on add new&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Add a post title, give it some content and don’t forget to give a short excerpt to summarise the new post&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Select the author&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Select the correct template in Post Attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;You can also set a featured image for the post if you’d like. Click on Set featured image.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Click on update on the right to save your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you refresh the page on your website your change or addition will now show. If not clear your browser's cache and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Editing pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;In the left menu click on pages&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Click on the title of the page you wish to edit&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;You can now edit the page's content&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Click on update on the right to save your changes&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you refresh the page on your website your change or addition will now show. If not clear your browser's cache and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Adding images to posts and pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;In the left menu click on media&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Click on add new and then drag and drop the images/files you'd like to upload&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Make sure that image/file names are all lowercase and are descriptive. Spaces in the image/file name should be denoted by a hyphen&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Once the images/files are uploaded you can insert them into your posts and pages.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Before you can start anything you need to log in, append wp-login.php to the end of your website address. Then enter your username and password.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bootstrap 3 the sass way</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-the-sass-way" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bootstrap 3 the sass way" /><published>2017-06-01T04:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T04:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-the-sass-way</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-the-sass-way">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;In this article, I'm going to go over Bootstrap and how to use it with SASS. I'll discuss the advantages that it can bring as a developer and some of the disadvantages that come along with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been using Bootstrap for about 4 years now. You could say that I'm pretty good at using it; well at least I thought I was good at it. When I started using Bootstrap I learnt how to use all of the componentry that comes with it. You can learn how to use all the components that the framework has to offer on the website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bootstrap documentation&quot;&gt;http://getbootstrap.com/&lt;/a&gt;. I learnt how to quickly develop websites with cool features like wells, thumbnails, carousels and much more. However, this didn't mean that I knew how to write the CSS that creates these components.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started to make sense once I had installed Bootstrap the SASS way. You need to know a couple of things to get it up and running. My workflow includes using Grunt to compile my SCSS via the command line. You can learn how to use Grunt via the command line quite easily: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gruntjs.com/getting-started&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Get started with Grunt&quot;&gt;https://gruntjs.com/getting-started&lt;/a&gt;. You can then install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twbs/bootstrap-sass&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bootstrap sass github &quot;&gt;bootstrap-sass&lt;/a&gt; using a package manager such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://yarnpkg.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Yarn Package Manager&quot;&gt;yarn&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bower.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bower Package Manager&quot;&gt;bower&lt;/a&gt;. Then all you have to do is compile a bootstrap.scss file using grunt and then reference your final CSS file in the head of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;med-margin-top min-margin-bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//codepen.io/akolinski/embed/OmKbMZ/?height=400&amp;theme-id=0&amp;default-tab=css&amp;embed-version=2&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; title=&quot;Bootstrap file scss&quot;&gt;See the Pen &amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io/akolinski/pen/OmKbMZ/&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39; href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io/akolinski/pen/OmKbMZ/&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;Bootstrap file scss&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt; by Adam Kolinski (&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io/akolinski&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39; href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io/akolinski&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;@akolinski&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;) on &amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;a data-cke-saved-href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39; href=&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;https://codepen.io&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;#39;&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;CodePen&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;/a&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;.&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reference to the codepen above, I have an example of the _bootstrap.scss file. You'll want to duplicate the _bootstrap.scss file and create your own version. Just so that you don't edit any of the core bootstrap files that you install using your package manager. This is the file that will be compiled by Grunt to create the final bootstrap.min.css file that you link to in the head of your website. As you can see each Bootstrap component is separated into its own SCSS file. This is how you can really learn what and how Bootstrap works. You can go into each SCSS file and see how that component was made. This has helped me understand and learn more about SCSS and CSS in general. You can start to learn how to use certain mixins and functions that Bootstrap has built in to help create new things. I'm sure I'll write an article in the future about a few of those mixins and functions. For now, I'll just introduce you to using Bootstrap with SASS in its purest form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing to keep in mind with this is to never edit any of the core Bootstrap files that are downloaded via the package manager. If you want to make edits create a duplicate copy of that file and reference it in your custom _bootstrap.scss file. This helps especially with when you want to update Bootstrap using your chosen package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the great advantages of having the variables file is that you can comment out any components that you're not using. This allows for your final compiled version of Bootstrap to be a smaller size. It goes hand in hand with how Google inspect element tools ask to only load CSS that is being used on the page the user is viewing. It also helps optimise your CSS delivery by having a smaller footprint. The only disadvantage here is you have to remember if you exclude a line in your _bootstrap.scss file. For example, if you include a well from the Bootstrap documentation and it isn't styled properly it’s because you haven't included it within your _bootstrap.scss file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another tip to take note of is how I have a bootstrap-variables file at the top of the codepen example. This is a copy of the file, line 5. The file should start off completely commented out. The Bootstrap variables file is a huge settings page that allows you to change general style elements in your Bootstrap theme. If you want to change certain parts of your Bootstrap theme you uncomment that line and make a change. This way you are not changing any of Bootstraps core files. For example, if you wanted to change the primary theme colour you could uncomment the $brand-primary variable and change the value to a colour you want to use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I say get on the bandwagon and enjoy the party because Bootstrap with SASS is here to stay. Not to mention that in &lt;a href=&quot;https://v4-alpha.getbootstrap.com/getting-started/introduction/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bootstrap 4 documentation&quot;&gt;Bootstrap 4&lt;/a&gt; they have switched from LESS to SASS for their source CSS files. So it'll be a good idea to start using it now in Bootstrap 3 and getting to grips with SASS in general. Reading through this website will get you started with SASS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Learn SASS&quot;&gt;http://sass-lang.com/guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">In this article, I'm going to go over Bootstrap and how to use it with SASS. I'll discuss the advantages that it can bring as a developer and some of the disadvantages that come along with that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Web design podcasts to listen to</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/web-design-podcasts-to-listen-to" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web design podcasts to listen to" /><published>2017-05-27T05:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-05-27T05:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/web-design-podcasts-to-listen-to</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/web-design-podcasts-to-listen-to">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;I write code for the most part of every day. Sometimes I listen to music but on occasion a Podcast on a topic that surrounds Web design. It helps me keep up to date with what's going on in the industry. Here are a few of my favourite Web design podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shoptalkshow.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Shop talk show&quot;&gt;1. ShopTalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Web Design and Development Podcast with Chris Coyier and Dave Rupert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frontendhappyhour.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Front End Happy Hour&quot;&gt;2. Front End Happy Hour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A podcast featuring a panel of Software Engineers from Netflix, Evernote, Atlassian &amp; LinkedIn talking over drinks about all things Front End development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uxpod.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;User Experience Podcast - UXpod&quot;&gt;3. User Experience Podcast - UXpod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A platform for discussing topics of interest to practitioners or others with an interest in UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://motionandmeaning.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Motion And Meaning&quot;&gt;4. Motion And Meaning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A podcast about motion for digital designers brought to you by Val Head and Cennydd Bowles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developertea.simplecast.fm/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Developer Tea&quot;&gt;5. Developer Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer Tea is a podcast for web and software developers hosted by a developer that you can listen to in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">I write code for the most part of every day. Sometimes I listen to music but on occasion a Podcast on a topic that surrounds Web design. It helps me keep up to date with what's going on in the industry. Here are a few of my favourite Web design podcasts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bootstrap 3 pages to save</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-pages-to-save" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bootstrap 3 pages to save" /><published>2017-04-24T06:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T06:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-pages-to-save</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-pages-to-save">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Being a Web designer is all about expanding your knowledge and seeing what is being done in the latest examples of our profession. It's for that reason I put together this list for the best tips, advice, freebies and tutorials I've collected over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bootswatch.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bootswatch&quot;&gt;1. Bootswatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootswatch is great for grabbing a predefined theme in bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://startbootstrap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Start Bootstrap&quot;&gt;2. Start Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start Bootstrap is a collection of free to download Bootstrap themes and templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bootstraphero.com/the-big-badass-list-of-twitter-bootstrap-resources&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The big badass list of useful Bootstrap resources&quot;&gt;3. The big badass list of useful Bootstrap resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly what the title describes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bootsnipp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Bootsnipp&quot;&gt;4. Bootsnipp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design elements, playground and code snippets for Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Being a Web designer is all about expanding your knowledge and seeing what is being done in the latest examples of our profession. It's for that reason I put together this list for the best tips, advice, freebies and tutorials I've collected over the years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Best website design blogs to follow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/best-website-design-blogs-to-follow" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best website design blogs to follow" /><published>2017-04-17T07:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-04-17T07:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/best-website-design-blogs-to-follow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/best-website-design-blogs-to-follow">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Being a Web designer is all about expanding your knowledge and seeing what is being done in the latest examples of our profession. It's for that reason I put together this list for the best tips, advice, freebies and tutorials I've collected over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;CSS Tricks&quot;&gt;1. CSS Tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips, Tricks, and Techniques on using Cascading Style Sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Codepen&quot;&gt;2. Codepen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demo or it didn't happen. Codepen is great for finding new examples for super cool web design demos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tutorialzine.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Tutorialzine&quot;&gt;3. Tutorialzine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tutorialzine is the one place for high-quality web development tutorials. Learn cutting edge techniques in web development and design, download open source components and participate in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tympanus.net/codrops/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Codrops&quot;&gt;4. Codrops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codrops is a web design and development blog that publishes articles and tutorials about the latest web trends, techniques and new possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scotch.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Scotch&quot;&gt;5. Scotch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scotch is a web development blog discussing all things programming, development, web, and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thecodinglove.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The coding love&quot;&gt;6. The coding love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is here to make you smile, laugh and just generally have a jolly good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uxreactions.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;UX Reactions&quot;&gt;7. UX Reactions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erm, today's word is procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Smashing magazine&quot;&gt;8. Smashing magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smashing Magazine, an online magazine for professional web designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cssauthor.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;CSS author&quot;&gt;9. CSS author&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web/Mobile design &amp; development blog, providing user interface design freebies, resources, articles, tools and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://davidwalsh.name/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;David Walsh Blog&quot;&gt;10. David Walsh Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blog featuring tutorials about JavaScript, HTML5, AJAX, PHP, CSS, WordPress, and everything else development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.commitstrip.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Commitstrip&quot;&gt;11. Commitstrip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is for all the GIT users out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://designmodo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Commitstrip&quot;&gt;12. Designmodo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designmodo publishes web design articles, tutorials and has a great shop with the best WordPress and Bootstrap themes, plugins, UI Kits and more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">Being a Web designer is all about expanding your knowledge and seeing what is being done in the latest examples of our profession. It's for that reason I put together this list for the best tips, advice, freebies and tutorials I've collected over the years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bootstrap 3 media queries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-media-queries" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bootstrap 3 media queries" /><published>2017-04-16T08:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-04-16T08:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-media-queries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/bootstrap-3-media-queries">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;I'm always having to refer to my favourite little cheat sheet when writing out media queries. I guess you can say that my brain got a little lazy. It's hard trying to remember the line of code that allows us to set specific CSS styles to certain viewports, or I'm simply making my life a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been using Bootstrap to build websites for quite some time now. So this code snippet is relative to the Bootstrap 3 implementation of the framework. You can read the documentation for building websites with Bootstrap on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. The documentation itself does go over the &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/css/#grid-media-queries&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;media queries&lt;/a&gt; in pretty much the same detail. I find it easier to refer to my own documentation on Github and I update it to make sure it aligns with Bootstrap most up to date implementation. Check out my code snippet on Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/EMPYmW&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://goo.gl/EMPYmW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/akolinski/29403de9ae9efbf56c8b5d5f3329e2ef.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">I'm always having to refer to my favourite little cheat sheet when writing out media queries. I guess you can say that my brain got a little lazy. It's hard trying to remember the line of code that allows us to set specific CSS styles to certain viewports, or I'm simply making my life a little easier.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website launch checklist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/website-launch-checklist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website launch checklist" /><published>2017-04-11T09:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2017-04-11T09:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/website-launch-checklist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/website-launch-checklist">&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;How can we guarantee that your website is launched in the best possible way? By following this checklist you can pat yourself on the back and have peace of mind that you have followed some essential web guidelines. This includes rules specified by the W3C, webAIM.org and Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all starts off with following this checklist. Carry out these checks and your website will be in a good shape in terms of Accessibility, Search engine optimisation (SEO) and Website speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
	&lt;thead&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Check&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/thead&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Follow proper heading hierarchy (H1, H2, H3, H4, H5, H6)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/techniques/semanticstructure/#correctly&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read more about semantic structure on webAIM.org&quot;&gt;Read more about semantic structure on webAIM.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;All images have good descriptive alternative 'ALT' text&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webaim.org/techniques/alttext/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read more about ALT text on webAIM.org&quot;&gt;Read more about ALT text on webAIM.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;All links have been checked and are not broken.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/NCUsH2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Check out this chrome extension to help check for broken links&quot;&gt;Check out this chrome extension to help check for broken links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;All images have descriptive filenames, hyphens indicate a word separator.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/KpVFLB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read about Google's image publishing guidelines&quot;&gt;Read about Google's image publishing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Anchors have meaningful text&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/QUh4Oj&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read the W3C guideline for providing link text that describes the purpose of a link&quot;&gt;Read the W3C guideline for providing link text that describes the purpose of a link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;All colors on backgrounds pass the Color contrast checker&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/LVISi8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Use the color contrast checker&quot;&gt;Use the color contrast checker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Forms have accessible elements. Meaningful labels using the for=&quot;&quot; attribute.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/TKMPnS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read about this guideline on the W3C website tutorial&quot;&gt;Read about this guideline on the W3C website tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Forms have accessible elements. Meaningful labels using the for=&quot;&quot; attribute.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/TKMPnS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Read about this guideline on the W3C website tutorial&quot;&gt;Read about this guideline on the W3C website tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Validate the HTML used on your website&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/w4MeQL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;The W3C Markup Validation Service&quot;&gt;The W3C Markup Validation Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Google PageSpeed score above 80&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/mAQ2vz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Get your PageSpeed score and use PageSpeed suggestions to make your web site faster&quot;&gt;Get your PageSpeed score and use PageSpeed suggestions to make your web site faster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Unique meta titles(70 character limit)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/qmmFud&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Matt Cutts from Google on creating good titles and snippets&quot;&gt;Matt Cutts from Google on creating good titles and snippets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Unique meta descriptions(160 character limit)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/QPah8D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Meta tags that Google understands&quot;&gt;Meta tags that Google understands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Google web master tool site verification&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/dPMUTO&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Get started with Google web master tools&quot;&gt;Get started with Google web master tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Create and submit sitemap on Google web master tools&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/djfwt1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Sitemap XML format&quot;&gt;Sitemap XML format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Crawl, fetch and submit new website pages on Google web master tools&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/pCXHN8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Use fetch as Google for websites&quot;&gt;Use fetch as Google for websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Add Google analytics code to website&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/L3ZZSy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Get started with Google analytics&quot;&gt;Get started with Google analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Use SVG where possible and images prepared for Retina&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/Bn1zic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Why aren’t you using SVG?&quot;&gt;Why aren’t you using SVG?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Koliński</name></author><summary type="html">How can we guarantee that your website is launched in the best possible way? By following this checklist you can pat yourself on the back and have peace of mind that you have followed some essential web guidelines. This includes rules specified by the W3C, webAIM.org and Google.</summary></entry></feed>